<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-06-20T16:48:19.493+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Add/Edit Enrolment Terms</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Add/Edit Enrolment Terms</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A <text style="font-weight:bold;">Term</text> is the period of time in which course, classes and other activities normally occur. Every class must be assigned at least one Term and may be assigned up to four in any one year.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If a class or activity occurs during a term break it is assigned to the term immediately preceding it. For example, If an activity occurs during the Term 1 to Term 2 break, it will be assigned to Term 1.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Once created, a Term cannot be deleted.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The Term record contains two important sets of dates...</para>
    <list id="0" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-weight:bold;">The Term Start &amp; End.</text> The start date is always a Monday. The end date is a calculated variable being the start date plus the number of weeks in the term as entered by you.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-weight:bold;">The enrolment Start &amp; End.</text> This is the date range in which new student enrolments will be assigned to the term. Typically, an enrolment period will start one week prior to the end of the previous term and end one week prior to the end of the current term. </li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If there is a period of time not covered by an enrolment period, then students will not be allowed to enrol. This is intended to allow the course coordinator time to prepare courses for the new year/term.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A timeline is provided within the procedure to assist in visualising term dates within the year.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">At any one time there is one and one only <text style="font-style:italic;">Default</text> or <text style="font-style:italic;">Current </text>term. Normally, this is set automatically after the last course for the term is complete. However, it can also be set manually by ticking the <text style="font-style:italic;">Is this the current term? </text>check box.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
