<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2024-10-27T20:10:31.820+11:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Add/Edit Contacts</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Add/Edit Contacts</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A <text style="font-weight:bold;">contact</text> can be any person associated with your U3A but is not a participant. Think of the list of contacts as your U3A&apos;s virtual Teledex.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">A contact may be assigned one or more <text style="font-weight:bold;">Tags</text>. A tag is simply a means of grouping like contacts together. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Use this procedure to maintain your list of contacts and tags. The procedure consists of three tabs...</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Contacts Tab</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Use this tab to add, edit or delete contacts. The fields on the contact record mimic the <text style="font-style:italic;">participant</text> fields discussed in the <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Add_Edit-Participants">Add/Edit Participants</link> topic. The major difference being a contact record only requires a First and Last Name. All other fields are optional. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The <text style="font-style:italic;">Email Address</text> field requires special note. Unlike the Participant email address, no validation of the contact email address is performed. It is therefore important that the email address be carefully checked before saving the record.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Contacts By Tag Tab</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">This tab provides a list of contacts grouped by tag. Note that a contact may be listed multiple times if it has been assigned multiple tags.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Add/Edit Tags Tab</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">This tab allows the addition of new Tags and the edit or deletion of existing tags. A tag has two properties...</para>
    <list id="0" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <list id="0" level="1" type="ol" listtype="lower-alpha" formatstring="&#37;&#49;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
        <li styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-style:italic;">Can Lead?</text> Contacts assigned the tag with this field checked will be permitted to lead classes.</li>
        <li styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-style:italic;">Can Enrol?</text> Contacts assigned the tag with this field checked will be permitted to enrol classes.</li>
      </list>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Refer to <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="The-difference-between-a-Parti">The difference between a Participant and a Contact</link> topic for a discussion of system behaviour when these fields are checked.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Both the Contacts tab and the Contacts By Tag tab have the ability to communicate with contacts. Review <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Communicate">Communicate</link> topic for details.</para>
  </body>
</topic>
