<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2024-05-05T16:34:13.970+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Class Attendance</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Class Attendance</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Normally, class attendance is a self-service activity performed by leaders, clerks or even participants via the <text style="font-style:italic;">Member Portal</text>. The procedure <text style="font-weight:bold;">Class Attendance</text> is therefore intended to allow administrators to make manual adjustment as required.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">To view or edit class attendance...</para>
    <list id="0" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="margin-bottom:0px; font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-bottom:0px;">Select the Term required. The software will default to the current enrolment term.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-bottom:0px;">Select the course required.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-bottom:0px;">Optionally, select the class required. Note that this field is only required when the course has different participants in each class.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-bottom:0px;">Select the class date required from the drop-down list</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-bottom:0px;"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px;">On entry of these details the current attendance status will be displayed in the grid, the leader&apos;s details and enrolment statistics will be displayed in the columns to the right. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px;">One of three attendance status may be assigned to a participant...</para>
    <list id="1" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px; margin-bottom:0px; font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px; margin-bottom:0px;">Absent without apology. This is the default status initially assigned.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px; margin-bottom:0px;">Absent with apology.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px; margin-bottom:0px;">Present</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-top:1px; margin-bottom:0px;"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">To assign an attendance status using the grid, edit the required row and select the status from the drop-down list. However, you will find it much quicker to assign the status using <text style="font-style:italic;">Quick Rollcall</text>.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Quick Rollcall</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">To assign an attendance status using Quick Rollcall simply select all enrollees with the same status on the grid. Then, in the <text style="font-style:italic;">Quick Rollcall</text> group box, select the status required, optionally enter a comment and click the <text style="font-style:italic;">Set Selection &#160;button.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Apply Student Leave</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Student leave details are created via the <text style="font-style:italic;">Member Portal</text>. Normally, such leave is applied to attendance once only when all attendance is assigned the default of <text style="font-style:italic;">Absent without apology</text>. Click this button to apply leave created after this event.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Reset Selected</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Click this button to reset selected attendance records. This procedure will delete the attendance record and then re-create it with a status of <text style="font-weight:bold;">Absent without apology</text>. </para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">It is especially useful in deleting duplicated records. In this instance, Filter the attendance records so that only those with a status of <text style="font-weight:bold;">Absent without apology</text> are displayed. Select and then click the <text style="font-weight:bold;">Reset Selection</text> button. This will delete all the selected records but only re-create those not duplicated.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Ad Hoc Attendance</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You may use this option to mark the attendance of any other participant attending the class but not formally enrolled. </para>
  </body>
</topic>
