<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-09-22T13:52:09.561+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Complimentary Membership</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Complimentary Membership</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Use this procedure at least once per year to assign complimentary membership to selected participants. Typically, complimentary membership means that membership fees are waived. Course fees may also be waived but this depends on options selected in <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Add_Edit-Courses">Add/Edit Courses</link>. Finally, postal fees may also be included as complimentary. This is defined in <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Membership-Fees">Membership Fees</link>.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Complimentary membership is applied to a year. The default year is the last year defined in <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Add_Edit-Enrolment-Terms">Add/Edit Enrolment Terms</link>. You may select an alternate year if required.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The software provides check boxes for you to identify membership groups to be made complimentary. The check box, <text style="font-style:italic;">Assign to Life members</text> is automatically ticked and cannot be unticked. All other check boxes are optional.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You may add complimentary membership to other members not otherwise part of the groups listed via the section titled, <text style="font-style:italic;">Assign Ad Hoc Complimentary Members. </text>Note that multiple members may be assigned simply by selecting multiple entries in the <text style="font-style:italic;">Assign to Members</text> editor. Use the <text style="font-style:italic;">Reason</text> field to explain why.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Finally, you may remove complimentary memberships previously assigned using the section titled, <text style="font-style:italic;">Remove Complimentary Membership</text>. Again, multiple participants may be removed at once.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When you are satisfied with your selection, click the <text style="font-weight:bold;">Process</text> button. After a short period of processing the system will return to the <text style="font-style:italic;">Home</text> screen. During processing the software will...</para>
    <list id="0" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; font-style:italic; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal">Set the <text style="font-style:italic;">Financial Year</text> to the year selected.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal">Create a zero-value cash receipt to document the complimentary status of the participant.</li>
    </list>
  </body>
</topic>
