<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-06-19T09:26:59.277+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Form</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Form</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Normally, data is entered via a <text style="font-style:italic;">Form</text>. A form is accessed usually via the grid or directly from the menu if a grid is not required.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">If accessed via the grid, that grid will have a combination of add, change or delete buttons. The buttons displayed will be determined by the developer. The <text style="font-style:italic;">Add</text> button is displayed as a plus (+) symbol on the grid&apos;s column header. The <text style="font-style:italic;">Edit</text> and <text style="font-style:italic;">Delete</text> buttons are displayed as a pencil and bin on each row respectively.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="grid edit buttons.png" imagestyleclass="Default" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption" figurelistinclude="0"></image></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The form is displayed as a modal window above the grid...</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="form.png" imagestyleclass="Default" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption" figurelistinclude="0"></image></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Enter the data as required and click the <text style="font-style:italic;">Save</text> button. If you are simply viewing the data, click the <text style="font-style:italic;">Cancel</text> button to ensure you do not save any unwanted changes.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When <text style="font-style:italic;">Save</text> is clicked, the software will validate your input. If there are issues the system will display messages to inform you of what needs to be changed. Change your input until it is acceptable and click <text style="font-style:italic;">Save</text> again.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Sometimes a form will contain a <text style="font-style:italic;">Discontinued</text> check box. This will be provided in place of the <text style="font-style:italic;">Delete</text> button on the grid. A discontinued record is a record you no longer require within the system, yet other records may depend on it so that it cannot be deleted. Discontinuing a record can therefore be thought of as a <text style="font-style:italic;">soft delete</text>; it is no longer available for use but remains to ensure data integrity within the database.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center; margin-bottom:0px;"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Hint:</text> Find Required Fields</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center;">To find all required fields on a new record, press the <text style="font-style:italic;">Save</text> button prior to entering any data. All required fields will be displayed as validation errors.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2">Data Editors</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Editors are the boxes into which you enter data. They range from the humble text box into which any character may be entered through to the rich text editor providing word processing functionality to the system.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">In between there are editors for each type of data; the date editor to enter dates, spin editor to enter whole numbers, selection editors to select one or more items from a list and editors to enter currency and decimal numbers. The purpose of these editors is to reduce the opportunity to enter invalid data into the database. Thus a date editor, for example will only accept valid dates.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">All editors other than the simple text editor will have a button to provide additional functionality via a drop-down window. This will be specific for the data type being entered. The date editor for example, will display a calendar from which to select the date. It is not compulsory to use the calendar as the date may be entered using the keyboard.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center; margin-bottom:0px; line-height:1.15;"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Hint: </text>Use <text style="font-style:italic;">Tab</text> to move between editors</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center; margin-bottom:0px; line-height:1.15;">Use the <text style="font-style:italic;">tab</text> key to move between editors. The tab key will move to the next editor in sequence. The SHIFT-tab combination will move to the previous editor. The tab key is a far more efficient method of data entry than using a mouse. Importantly, it reduces the potential of Repetitive Strain Injury (RSI) that can accompany heavy mouse use.</para>
  </body>
</topic>
