<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2024-12-12T12:47:15.079+11:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>How to safely move a class between terms</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">How to safely move a class between terms</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When a participant enrolls in a class, that enrollment is tied to the current enrollment &#160;term or the term in which the class first occurs. As we move from one term to the next those enrollments are <text style="font-style:italic;">brought forward</text> into the new term.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Sometimes, you may have a class that occurs in one term only that has to be moved to a later term. For example, an excursion that has been postponed from term 3 to term 4 because of inclement weather. Simply, changing the class start date will cause all enrollments to be lost (because the enrollments are tied to term 3).</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">To make the change and keep all enrollments, perform the following steps...</para>
    <list id="0" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Segoe UI&apos;; font-size:11pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal">Using <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Add_Edit-Courses">Add/Edit Courses</link> create a new class record for the course. Keep all details for the new class the same as the original class except for the new start date. At completion of this step you will have a course with two classes.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal">Using <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Enrol-Participants">Enrol Participants</link> transfer (move) all enrollments from the original class to the new class.</li>
      <li styleclass="Normal">Go back to <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Add_Edit-Courses">Add/Edit Courses</link> and delete delete the original class.</li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal">When the above steps are complete, your course will have been moved to the new term and all enrollments will remain intact.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"> &#160;</para>
  </body>
</topic>
