<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-06-17T15:43:39.341+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Increased Spam Email Activity</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Increased Spam Email Activity</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Unfortunately, increased spam email activity is often associated with sending email in bulk. If email is sent to hundreds of members, chances are that one or more of those members are using a compromised device. They have transmitted your email address to one or more likely many bad actors.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center;"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Rules:</text>&#32;</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center; margin-bottom:0px;">1. Never open junk email</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center; margin-bottom:0px;">2. Never click on a link contained in junk email</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center; margin-bottom:0px;">3. Never download junk email images or click on them</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center;">4. Never forward junk email to friends or technicians</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-align:center;">Breaking these rules simply informs the bad actor the email address is real.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Spam email arrives in your Inbox</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Best to delete it as that will save you from occidentally opening it in future. </para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Spam email arrives in your Junk Mail folder</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Most spam and other malicious email is caught by your email server such as Office 365. Spam will appear in your Junk Email folder when these systems determine an email is suspected junk but without a high degree of certainty.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Its your choice. You can simply leave it there and your software will eventually delete it. Or, you can delete it yourself.</para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3">Can anything else be done</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Yes, if the U3A group is using Office 365, the spam tolerance levels can be adjusted. This is an advanced topic and should only be performed if the volume of spam has become intolerable. The issue with making such adjustments is that you increase the likelihood of false-positives. That is, email identified by the server as spam but in fact is not.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can report spam the the Australian Consumer &amp; Competition Commission&apos;s Scamwatch program <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://www.scamwatch.gov.au/report-a-scam" target="_blank">here</link>.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can report spam to the Australian Media &amp; Communications Authority <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://www.acma.gov.au/spam-complaint-form" target="_blank">here</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">You can report spam directly to Microsoft by dragging and dropping the offending email into a new email to <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="mailto:abuse@microsoftonline.com">abuse@microsoftonline.com</link>.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Finally, learn about best practise using the Internet and email. The <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://www.cyber.gov.au/learn-basics/explore-basics/recognise-and-report-scams" target="_blank">Australian Cyber Security Centre</link> is a good place to start. </para>
  </body>
</topic>
