<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2025-07-21T11:41:50.285+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>Theme &amp; Settings</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">Theme &amp; Settings</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The Theme &amp; Settings module allows you to customise your workspace to your liking. The preferences chosen affect only your device. They do not affect any other device using the system.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The options available are...</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="7" colcount="2">
      <thead style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Setting Option</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Description</para>
        </td>
      </thead>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Theme</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Our software uses a single theme known as fluent. You may choose a mode being, <text style="font-style:italic;">Fluent Light</text> or <text style="font-style:italic;">Fluent Dark</text>. The mode determines the theme background and alters coloring to suit.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Menu Style</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Choose from <text style="font-style:italic;">Sidebar</text> or <text style="font-style:italic;">Top Menu</text> style. The sidebar places the menu on the left hand side of your workspace, while the top menu is placed at the top of the screen.</para>
          <para styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Hint</text>: Choose a menu style that maximises your workspace depending on the aspect ratio of your device. On devices that are wider in width than height (for example: 16x9) a sidebar is probably more appropriate. On square shaped devices, a top menu might be more to your liking.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Menu Behaviour</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">By default, the menu will automatically adjust to your device&apos;s screen size. On larger devices it is fully displayed, and hidden on smaller devices to maximise screen size.</para>
          <para styleclass="Normal">If this behavior is not to your liking, choose a behavior from the list provided. </para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Sidebar Image</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">An random image will be displayed in the bottom right hand corner of your workspace if the sidebar menu style is chosen.</para>
          <para styleclass="Normal">You may choose a fixed image or none at all if you so desire.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Font Size</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">The system comes with three pre-determined font sizes; small, medium and large. By default, the small size is used.</para>
          <para styleclass="Normal">You may choose a font size to your personal preference. Alternatively, hold the CTRL key down and scroll your mouse wheel to change the browser&apos;s font size.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td style="width:194px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">Accent Color</para>
        </td>
        <td style="width:740px;">
          <para styleclass="Normal">The fluent them has one primary or accent color. Choose the color to your liking.</para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
  </body>
</topic>
