<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-06-19T08:26:35.130+10:00" lasteditedby="hanlo" version="2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title>UI Components</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1">UI Components</para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Within a U3Admin display page UI components are used to accept user interactions, display information and input data.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-weight:bold;">User Interaction</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The most common user interaction is site navigation. This is performed via the application&apos;s <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Main-Menu">main menu</link>. You may also find standard navigation links within the software, especially this help system. The <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Main-Menu">main menu</link> link above is one such example. Within our software links are most often displayed as buttons, <link displaytype="button" type="topiclink" href="Main-Menu">Main Menu</link></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Display Information</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">The <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Grid">grid</link> is the primary means by which two-dimensional data is displayed on-screen. This is a spreadsheet-like component that displays data in rows and columns. Columns can be sorted, grouped and filtered. The grid can be exported to Excel for in-depth analysis and printing.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">One-dimensional data such as a single participant record will normally be displayed in a <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Form">form</link>. Forms consist of fields into which data is entered and/or changed. Normally, forms are accessed by clicking the add or edit button on the required row of a grid.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Finally, data is displayed in <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Report">reports</link>. A report is a formal document and is usually intended for printing. As such it is not editable. However, reports can be exported to Excel in which they can be edited. Information on a report can be searched and usually simple filtering is also available.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text style="font-weight:bold;">Input Data</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal">Data is entered via a <link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Form">form</link> as discussed above. The components used to enter data are known as editors. Each distinct data type owns it&apos;s own editor. A text editor allows the entry of text, a date editor the entry of date and time, a check box the entry of true/false values and so on. There are many editors ranging from the humble text editor through to the complex rich-text editor that incorporates many of the features found in a word processor.</para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
